Guide to the Raphael Lemkin (1900-1959) Collection, 1763-2002 (bulk 1941-1951)
P-154
- Series IV: Publications, undated, 1915-1919, 1944, 1946-1952; Boxes 10-12.
  The publications include United Nations-related brochures, writings within general journals and law association journals on the Genocide Convention, and source materials from magazines, bulletins, and pamphlets from publications concerning genocide-related issues of the 20th century. The source materials publications are of particular interest. Included in this section are several copies of the magazine Hellenia: The Voice of Greek Women, from 1949-1950 with articles on general women's issues in Greece as well as information on the abduction of children by Communist guerillas; several issues of the Lithuanian Bulletin from 1946-1950 with articles concerning the conflict between the Baltic countries and the Soviet Union as well as other publications detailing related atrocities; publications from 1915-1919 concerning Turkey and Armenia, and several pamphlets from the Pakistani viewpoint concerning issues regarding allegations of genocide against Muslims in Kashmir and India dating from 1948.
  - Series II: Genocide Convention. Subseries 2: United Nations, 1948, 1952
    - "Convention on Genocide: What the United Nations is Doing", 1952 edition (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "United States Participation in the United Nations: Report by the President to the Congress for the Year", April 1948 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Series II: Genocide Convention. Subseries 3: Writings, 1947-1951
    - Journal Articles, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Journal Articles, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Journal Articles, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Law Association Journals, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Law Association Journals, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Series III: History of Genocide. Subseries 1: Source Materials Publications, 1915-1919, 1944-1951
    - Greece-Abduction of Children by Communist Guerillas, [Hellenia: The Voice of Greek Women Magazine], 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - India-Pakistan Pamphlets, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Soviet Union-Baltic States Publications, 1944, 1948-1951 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Soviet Union-Baltic States [Lithuanian Bulletin], 1946-1947 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Union-Baltic States [Lithuanian Bulletin], 1947-1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Turkey - Armenian Publications, 1915-1919, 1946-1948 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Series V: Restricted Documents, various dates; Box 13.
  The documents are arranged by series in alphabetical order.
  This series contains fragile and yellowing documents removed from the general collection for preservation purposes. All materials have been photocopied with copies placed within the original folder for research purposes.All documents in this series are restricted due to their fragile condition.
  - Series I, Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Series II, Articles by Lemkin (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Series II, Articles Mentioning or Citing Lemkin (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Series II, Lemkin Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Series II, Notes and Drafts (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Series II, Statements, Resolutions and Memoranda (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Series II, United Nations (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Series II, Unpublished Essays (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Series III, Research Essays (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Series III, Research Notes (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Series III, Source Materials (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Oversized Materials, undated, 1944-1945, 1947-1951; Box 14.
  Documents are arranged by series in alphabetical order.
  Oversized materials primarily consist of original clippings pulled from the collection, unfolded and placed in flat storage. All clippings have been photocopied with copies placed within the original folder for research purposes. Unless otherwise noted, all materials are restricted. Folder 6 and folder 7 contain materials that may be used by researchers including a U.S. Committee for a U.N. Genocide Convention poster with photographs and quotes by members of the committee and a poster of the Genocide Conventions. Folder 7 contains various oversized source materials. This folder is shared with restricted source material clippings.
  - Series I: Clippings, Biographical(Restricted), undated, 1947-1948, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Series II: Clippings(Restricted), undated, 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Series II: Clippings by Lemkin(Restricted), 1948-1951 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Series II: Clippings Mentioning or Citing Lemkin(Restricted), undated 1944, 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Series II: Genocide and Genocide Convention Scrapbook(Restricted), undated 1947-1948 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Series II: U.S. Committee for a U.N. Genocide Convention Committee Poster and Convention Text (Fact Sheets, Informational Materials), undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Series III: Source Materials Clippings and Misc. Source Material(Clippings restricted), undated, 1945, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 7)